Ahmed Mohamed Mohamed Hassanien

Software Testing Engineer

PROFILE

Experienced Software Testing Engineer skilled in manual and automation testing. I excel in designing and executing test cases, detecting bugs, and reporting them effectively. I have strong experience in Performance, API and Automation using Selenium, RestAssured and Appium, alongside basic knowledge in CI/CD.

EDUCATION

Higher Institute for Engineering and Technology MIE

10/2018 - 05/2023

Major: Electrical Engineering (Electronics and Communication Engineering).

Cairo, Egypt

Overall Grade: Excellent (87.19%).

Graduation Project: FOTA System for Smart Vehicles.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Engineer07/2024 – presentGivers - Part TimeCairo, Egypt

• Created and implemented test strategy, test policy, and detailed test plan.

- Created detailed test cases and scenarios that cover functional and non-functional testing.
- Testing UI/UX designs in Figma to evaluate the user interface and user experience.
- API Manual Testing using Postman.

Quality Control Engineer04/2024 - presentComRec Solutions - Full TimeCairo, Egypt

- Create effective test cases based on requirements and functional specifications.
- Execute test cases to ensure the functionality, and reliability of software Applications.
- Identify, document, and report defects or issues found during testing.
- Conduct regression testing to ensure that new feature do not negatively impact functionality.

Quality Control Engineer
ITWORX Education - Internship

02/2024 – 04/2024 Cairo, Egypt

• Create detailed, structured test cases for comprehensive coverage.

- Conduct regression testing upon the resolution of identified software defects.
- Create bug reports using Jira.
- Apply Security Testing using OWASP Zap.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

• Java, JavaScript and Python.

Conceptual knowledge

• OOP Concepts, Data Structures and Algorithms.

Manual Testing

- Quality Engineering Methodologies and Software Testing Concepts & Techniques (ISTQB).
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC).
- Read, Understand and Review Business Requirements Documents (BRD).
- Manual Testing (Writing Test Scenarios, Test Cases and Bug Reports).
- API Testing using Swagger and Postman & Newman tools.
- Web and Mobile UI Testing.
- SQL and Database Testing.

Automation Testing

- Automation Web UI Testing with Selenium (Java), TestNG, BDD (Cucumber), POM, DataDriven.
- UI and API Automation Testing with Shaft Engine.
- UI and API Automation Testing with Katalon.
- Automation Mobile UI Testing with Appium.
- API Automation Testing with Rest Assured.

Non-Functional Testing

- Web Performance Testing with Jmeter.
- Security Testing using OWASP Zap.

SDLC

- Waterfall.
- V-Model.
- Agile Methodologies: Scrum, Kanban.

Tool

Azure DevOps, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, Git - GitHub, CucumberStudio, Apache Jmeter and Postman.

PROJECTS

1 KO)Le15	
Givers Mobile Application Manual and Automation Mobile Testing Mobile application that connects volunteers with local charitable opportunities.	07/2024
Hospital Management System <i>⊗</i> Manual Testing ComRec Product specialized in recording and managing Electronic Medical Records (EMR).	04/2024
Automation Exercise API using Shaft Engine \mathscr{D} Automating REST API endpoints using with reporting and ensuring that they meet the expected functionality and behavior for an E-commerce website.	04/2024
Automation Exercise UI using Shaft Engine <i>⊗</i> Web Automation Project Automating Test cases with reporting for an E-commerce website called Automation Exercise.	04/2024
SIS <i>⊗ Manual Testing</i> Software project about ministry of education in Emirates.	03/2024
WinjiGo ℰ Manual Testing Software project about education in Emirates.	02/2024
Spotify API ⊗ API Automation Testing Testing Spotify APIs using Rest-assured library based on Spotify documentation.	01/2024
Demo Nop Commerce Website Web UI Automation Automating positive and negative Test cases for various features.	12/2023
Ksrtc Website Automation Web UI Automation Automated booking process on KSRTC website (handling E2E cycle).	11/2023
Pet Store Automation \mathscr{D} API Automation Testing Automating different test cases for Rest API endpoints on Swagger Pet store with reporting.	11/2023
COURSES	
Appium Course with Java	05/2024
Rest Assured API Automation	03/2024
Selenium WebDriver with Cucumber	01/2024
Selenium WebDriver and TestNG Course	11/2023
Software Testing Bootcamp	06/2023
CERTIFICATES	
ISTQB Foundation Level Code - 240723042	
LANGUAGES	
A 1:	

• • • • •

Arabic $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$ English